Zaid Yazadi

Chicago, IL 60611 (408) 444-2786 <u>zyazadi2000@gmail.com</u> http://www.linkedin.com/in/zaid-vazadi

Personal Website:

https://zv-131.github.io

Motivated computer engineering graduate with a proven track record in software engineering, cloud technology, and project leadership. Strong coding skills in Java and Python, combined with experience in AWS and CI/CD. Committed to driving efficiency, innovation, and excellence in every project.

Education

Pennsylvania State University, State College, PA

June 2018 – May 2022 (**B.S. in Computer Engineering**)

• Dean's List (GPA: 3.79)

Skills

- Coding Languages: Java, Python, Angular, HTML, JavaScript, SQL, C/C++, XML, Verilog, Bash
- **Technology Experience**: Git, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Docker, Jenkins, Express, Node.JS, PostgreSQL, gRPC, REST API, JPOS, TSYS, Postman, ServiceNow, SSL Certificate Management, and Unity VR development
- **Testing/Monitoring Software:** Splunk, DataDog, NewRelic, OneLake, PagerDuty, JUnit, Cucumber, Apache JMeter
- Bilingual in Urdu and English

Experience

CAPITAL ONE, CHICAGO, IL

Associate Software Engineer (Card Tech), August 2022 – Current

- Collaborated in maintenance, updates, and testing of Payment Authorization gateways for various 3rd-party partners using a multitude of Cloud, CI/CD, and testing tools
- Presented new production onboarding initiative for new partner gateways while meeting internal/external requirements to upper-level management
- Co-led implementation of new authorization gateway design plan which reduced cost overhead, increased work efficiency, and decreased resource utilization
- Trained in a variety of technological/professional skills within the Technical Development Program

CAPITAL ONE, MCLEAN, VA

Software Engineering Intern (Cloud & Productivity), June 2021 – August 2021

- Aided in cloud maintenance initiative by developing a quarterly-run AWS Security Group Audit System on company-wide cloud infrastructure to monitor low-usage resources (4 intern team)
- · Led development of AWS Lambda Notification Engine to notify owners of low usage resources
- Studied and implemented secure coding practices to prevent listed OWASP vulnerabilities
- · Attended multiple webinars/trainings for a variety of topics including technology & leadership
- Met with a variety of upper-level management and executives to discuss career development, professional experience, and company outlooks

AIRV LABS / SIMULATED SURGICAL SYSTEMS, SAN JOSE, CA

Software Engineering Intern, June 2020 – August 2020

- · Tested Robotic Surgery Simulation Software for functionality before client product demonstration
- · Tested Nibiru HMD for software compatibility which led to decreases in development costs
- Assisted in the creation of a patent application for VR telecommunication product

IBM, SAN JOSE, CA

Federal Sector Early ID Program, June 2020 – November 2020

- · Attended multiple webinars geared to advance students in federal consulting roles
- Won Case Project Competition (decreasing accreditation fraud and cost of Federal Accreditation Process w/ use of automation & ML) in team of 2 other mentees in varying fields of expertise

Awards & Honors

EAGLE SCOUT, TROOP 251 - Silicon Valley Monterey Bay Council (055) – August 30, 2017

• Eagle Project: Created and led Coat and Toy Drive for Syrian refugees

AWARD OF APPRECIATION - Helping Hand, San Jose, CA (https://www.hhrd.org/)

· For organizing & leading various charity drives and fundraisers